<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>lai.victor</title>
 <link href="" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://www.laivictor.com"/>
 <updated>2012-08-20T21:26:54-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://www.laivictor.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Victor Lai</name>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title type="html">tetris friends does tetris right - pt. 1</title>
   <link href="http://www.laivictor.com/archive/2012/08/19/whattetrisdoesright"/>
   <updated>2012-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.laivictor.com/archive/2012/08/19/whattetrisdoesright</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
  I recently got to level 95 in Tetris Friends Battle 2P and 6P, so here's some Tetris.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tetris'&gt;Tetris&lt;/a&gt; is somewhat of a famous game. Most people who've played it probably first
  started on the GameBoy. Maybe something like this.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src='http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/4/4a/GB_Tetris.png' /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  Nowadays, &lt;a href='http://www.tetrisfriends.com/' target='_blank'&gt;Tetris Friends&lt;/a&gt; is all the rage. 
  And for good reason.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  They sort of have a monopoly on the casual Tetris scene, being the licensee in North America. They have a dedicated site and an app on Facebook. 
  And actually, it probably wouldn't be wrong to say that Tetris Friends is the reason Tetris has gotten a recent resurgence.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  The Tetris Friends has several game modes in both Single Player and Multiplayer. Marathon, where you try to clear as many lines as possible,
  to Sprint 5P, where you play 3 others to finish 40 lines in the fastest time, to Battle 2P, where you battle another player and score KOs.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  My main experience is with the Multiplayer Battle modes, so that's where my point of view will be from.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  In May, one of my high school friends saw me playing Tetris, and asked me for a match. I hadn't seen him in a while, so why not.
  In short, he crushed me. Long version, he REALLY crushed me. I thought I was decent. He was Level 100, literally a Tetris God (more on that later).
  I vowed that day to get to a point where I could compete toe-to-toe with him. At least, somewhere toe-to-toe. It was a game, and it was a 
  fun challenge. My favourite kind.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  Over the last 3 months, I played Tetris Friends pretty religiously. After work, a couple hours. On the weekends, a couple hours. Nothing too crazy,
  but it got me really into the game, and to a point where I could see a vast improvement over my nooby May self. It was very rewarding to realize
  that putting this determination into something actually paid off. Yay!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  I said my main experience was on Battle 2P and Battle 6P. Battle 2P is the most... competitive game mode. You play another player from around the world,
  send as many lines as possible to the other player, and hope you KO them more than they do to you. To send lines, you'll have to perform combos, either 
  consecutively or with a T-spin. Along the way, you'll also have to clear the lines that your opponent sends to you by clearing the bombs away. It's complicated,
  but play a few times and you'll get the gist of it. Here's a image I found off Google.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img class='scale-with-grid child-padding' src='http://i.ytimg.com/vi/AHdBNRff2AY/0.jpg' /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
  Starting off, you'll be pretty bad, but if you play well and know how to improve, you'll do fine. At least I did.
  Notice that knowing how to improve is really important. There's a lot of players that are really good, but really good with a bad style, and that hinders
  their improvement. Theoretically, your skill ceiling is near limitless in this game, when you play as faster as your computer can process. But realistically, 
  it slows down to a crawl once you've exhausted your play style.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  Most players in the game know of only one way to play. I will refer to this as the 1-line style. Since the board is 10 spaces across, they'll fill up
  9 of those spaces as high as possible (preferably leaving the 1 space at the left or right side), while saving up the I-piece, then drop it twice for 
  a Tetris, then a Back-to-Back Tetris. This is pretty good for low levels, and it's so simple, it'll help develop your building skills faster. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
  But definitely, it's the worst way to play.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  Before I move on, I want to focus on some essential &quot;pillars&quot; of playing Battle Tetris. &lt;br /&gt;
	- Opening &lt;br /&gt;
	- Build-up &lt;br /&gt;
	- Combos &lt;br /&gt;
	- Anticipation &lt;br /&gt;
	- Bomb Clearing &lt;br /&gt;
	- Ending &lt;br /&gt;
  Well, that's a lot of new stuff. Let's take a look at the important ones
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  The opening is really irrelevant for low levels of play. Once you get higher, the opening could score you lots of easy points, and set you up for the entire game.
  Contrary to popular belief, anticipating your opponent really isn't necessary until the higher levels. By simply out-performing your opponent, you can win very easily.
  Similarly, bomb clearing is unnecessary. If you play well, taking the KO means you can combo longer. The ending is also unnecessary. While you want to finish
  with as few blocks as possible, only the highest level players care about it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  So we're left with build-up and combos. Build-up describes the speed and accuracy of how high you can get your stack. If you build-up very well, you have very
  solid mechanics, don't make many mistakes, understand what to look for in your stack, make good decisions on-the-fly, understand patterns, look several moves ahead, 
  and perform at great pace. This is the main focus of Tetris Friends. Building a solid foundation so you can do the wacky things you want. Most often though, this is 
  limited by the second part, combos.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  Combo-ing is the act of sending lines to your opponent to KO them. You can achieve this several ways. One way is the Back-to-Back Tetris I mentioned earlier, in which
  you have two I-pieces in a row and you Tetris twice with a stack greater than 8 rows high. However, a golden principle to note is that if you're combo-ing, you want to 
  use as few lines per piece as possible. With a Tetris, every piece (I-piece) you use, will use up 4 lines of your stack. This is not good, because bonuses get much, much higher
  when you maintain a long consecutive combo. That is, if every piece you use clears at least one line, and you use more than 1 piece. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  This is where me saying that the 1-line style is bad. Thinking about it, the ratio of time spent building up the stack versus the amount of lines sent to your opponent, 
  is definitely way too low. Beginners are a lot better matched to play the 2-line style, where you build up in 8 spaces, leaving a 2 space gap on a side of your stack,
  then dropping pieces to form a combo. You can easily get an 8 or 9 combo after a few tries, which is much better, and time effective than 1-line. And it means you can
  attack your opponent (by sending lines), at almost any point you feel like it. 2-line seems to counter 1-line pretty well, but it still depends largely on your speed.
  I will continue on in my next post.
&lt;/p&gt;</content>
   
   <category term="tetris"/>
   
   <category term="gaming"/>
   
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title type="html">some cables feel really nice</title>
   <link href="http://www.laivictor.com/archive/2012/08/11/reallynicecables"/>
   <updated>2012-08-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.laivictor.com/archive/2012/08/11/reallynicecables</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
  I recently gained possession of a really nice pair of cables. 1/4&quot; male to 1/4&quot; male. Nothing 
  special really, except the cable feels really nice.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
  I have a pair of &lt;a href='http://www.moon-audio.com/audio-cables/moon-audio-headphone-cables/moon-audio-blue-dragon-headphone-cable.html'&gt;Blue Dragon&lt;/a&gt; cables from Moon-Audio. Apparently it's surrounded by Kevlar
  and Teflon tape. Yum. That link isn't the same pair, but it's close. It feels like a really high quality 
  braided cable. All newer Razer peripherals come braided with a &lt;a href='http://cdn.theendearingdesigner.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/Razer-Naga-Gaming-Mouse-Review14.jpg'&gt;cloth like material&lt;/a&gt;. 
  It feels nice, but the Blue Dragon cable is less flexible, with a really strong and plasticky feel. 
  It feels amazing.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  My new cable feels even better. It's completely rubberized, which isn't something I've seen a lot.
  The rubber is really textured, unlike the smooth plasticky rubber on a lot of cables. It's 
  made by Fender, and says Professional Noiseless Cable on the cable itself. I don't know why that message is required. 
  Isn't that expected of every cable? 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  Oh well. It feels so nice I don't mind.
&lt;/p&gt;</content>
   
   <category term="music"/>
   
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title type="html">Tools - Dexpot</title>
   <link href="http://www.laivictor.com/archive/2012/08/03/toolsdexpot"/>
   <updated>2012-08-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.laivictor.com/archive/2012/08/03/toolsdexpot</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
  When I first used Ubuntu, I fell in love with graphical 
  &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Workspace#Graphical_interfaces' target='_blank'&gt;workspaces&lt;/a&gt;.
  The ability to open and manage multiple desktops was a great implementation when you only have one monitor. 
  The controls were intuitive, the  transitions were clean and delays were non-existent. 
  It was an amazing discovery.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  I later found out that Apple's OS X has the Expose and Spaces for their own version of workspaces. 
  It is noticeably faster, more responsive and applied better features, as expected on the very well 
  designed Mac OS. As a Windows user primarily however, I felt very left out.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  After a lot of searching, I found the solution. &lt;a href='http://dexpot.de/' target='_blank'&gt;Dexpot&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  They've made a lot of improvements since I've first time I used it, and right now, it's evolved into something
  beautiful. They've added much better taskbar integration, a less buggy multi-monitor support, and much, much better 
  responsiveness overall. It's a great product with a great team behind it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  Simply put, virtual desktops allow one to swap between screens. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  The main benefit is clutter. Spacing out several applications over four screens is great, similar to the benefits
  of using multiple monitors. It means you can categorize your workspaces, one section for reference applications, 
  one side for working programs, and another area for anything else.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  Keeping the programs maximized like this means the program is almost always active. Minimizing and maximizing is 
  a drag, while with Dexpot or any virtual desktop application, pressing a customized key combination, say ALT+1 or 
  ALT+2, will swap the active applications to a new set. It's much more convenient.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  The difference in productivity is pretty astounding. Give it a go &lt;a href='http://dexpot.de/?id=download' target='_blank'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;</content>
   
   <category term="tools"/>
   
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title type="html">site (re)construction</title>
   <link href="http://www.laivictor.com/archive/2012/07/29/siterestructure"/>
   <updated>2012-07-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.laivictor.com/archive/2012/07/29/siterestructure</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
  It is ridiculous how hard it is to rework an entire website. Currently, the site is pretty bad
  for mobile, plus it doesn't act the way I want it when the window is resized. I plan to fix that.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  Meanwhile, expect a lot more breaking in the future.
&lt;/p&gt;</content>
   
   <category term="site"/>
   
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title type="html">saved by dropbox</title>
   <link href="http://www.laivictor.com/archive/2012/07/26/dropboxmagic"/>
   <updated>2012-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.laivictor.com/archive/2012/07/26/dropboxmagic</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href='http://www.dropbox.com' target='_blank'&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; is amazing.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  Because I use some slightly more complicated system with GitHub and Dropbox, 
  I had to learn some new stuff so that I could upload my website properly to GitHub Pages.
  The first time I tried it, I actually deleted my website files, along with the 
  GitHub repository. I had nothing to roll back to. It was all gone.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  But to my joy, I always debated whether to put the website source in my Dropbox, so I could
  work on it and sync my files across my computers. So I left it on my Dropbox this time.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  When I accidentally deleted my website files, I found out that Dropbox saves a history of your deleted
  files, so that you can recover them if they go accidentally, and actually use them as a mini-version
  tracker. Awesome for a free service.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  Thank you very much Dropbox, for saving a couple days' or weeks' worth of material. Thank you.
&lt;/p&gt;</content>
   
   <category term="utils"/>
   
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title type="html">just go for it</title>
   <link href="http://www.laivictor.com/archive/2012/07/20/justgoforit"/>
   <updated>2012-07-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.laivictor.com/archive/2012/07/20/justgoforit</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
  When people ask for motivation, it's really hard to give them a straight answer. 
  I never had one myself. But recently, I've had some really bad problems that 
  left me scratching my head. I couldn't solve it, and there was nothing I could do.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  But then I came along a couple of really good motivational posts, which really,
  in essence, told me to do it because failure is not an option. Mediocrity is not an option.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  And that's what I've always believed in. My motivation was always really, 
  &quot;Do it because you can. Do it to prove to yourself that you can. 
  Do it 100% because when it's all over, you're still an insignificant speck,
  unless your 100% is better than his.&quot; Talk about an inferiority complex going on here.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  But I realized, I grew into a habit of accepting mediocrity. It might be because the university 
  system forces this down our throats a bunch, and some life-changing realizations I've made since. 
  I shouldn't be making excuses for my failures, because there isn't time in life to do this.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  
&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='console'&gt;&lt;span class='go'&gt;60sec * 60min * 24hr * 365.25days * 100 yrs = 3,155,760,000 seconds. Not enough.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  I can't let one little thing set me back so much of that time. Just as much as I can't do something
  50%, and then complain about it later on.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  Screw getting the motivation. I'll just do it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;a href='http://youtu.be/Sk56VxaeqEQ' target='_blank'&gt;The BEST Motivation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  &quot;You need to ask yourself, 'what are you going to do today,' &lt;br /&gt;
  but more importantly, 'how are you going to do it.'&quot;
&lt;/p&gt;</content>
   
   <category term="misc"/>
   
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title type="html">counterstrike &amp; memories</title>
   <link href="http://www.laivictor.com/archive/2012/07/11/counter-memories"/>
   <updated>2012-07-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.laivictor.com/archive/2012/07/11/counter-memories</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
  Sometimes, the oddest of circumstances makes you remember things you did in 
  the past, that somehow you forgot over the years. And most of the time, it puts a 
  really big smile on your face when you remember.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 
  I was having an innocent argument with an artist about stuff that we've made in the 
  past. While my friend is clearly the better artist between the two of us, I remembered
  that I really wanted to be a (graphic) artist at some point in my life. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  My Grade 9 Art mark was an astounding 100, a surprise, even to myself. I think my 
  Art teacher had a lot of hope in me, and was probably a little heartbroken when me 
  and my friend (who also got 100), decided not to take Grade 10 Art.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  Since Grade 5 or 6, I have always been the biggest Counter-Strike fan, until some 
  tragic event a couple of years ago that forced me to quit. I played a lot of Counter-Strike, 
  so I'm pretty sure my 662 HOURS PLAYED on Steam is inaccurate. In my spare time then, 
  I thought about Counter-Strike a lot. But that's for another time.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  One day, I stumbled upon a thriving online game modding community in 
  &lt;a href='http://www.fpsbanana.com' target='_blank'&gt;FPSBanana&lt;/a&gt;. Immediately I was hooked. 
  The most memorable member was &lt;a href='http://gamebanana.com/members/164481' target='_blank'&gt;Teh Snake&lt;/a&gt;.
  He made so many brilliant and amazing mods, he really was the reason I wanted to go into graphic design.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  Eventually, I tried my hand at modding, and upon realizing I had no talent,
  I tried something much, much easier, and something that brings me joy to see online to this very day.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
  I made a custom hand skin for CS1.6 and CZ after collaborating with the original owner, Nasaratsu.
  Here's the &lt;a href='http://gamebanana.com/cscz/skins/48319' target='_blank'&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;, and while it's 
  really bad, I'm still extremely proud of it. Over 6,000 downloads, and 14,000 views. :')
&lt;/p&gt;</content>
   
   <category term="memories"/>
   
   <category term="counterstrike"/>
   
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title type="html">first coding interview</title>
   <link href="http://www.laivictor.com/archive/2012/04/14/failinterview"/>
   <updated>2012-04-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.laivictor.com/archive/2012/04/14/failinterview</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
I had an interview the other day that really shook me up.

He asked me a question that really made me wonder how much I really knew about programming. 
I really thought I knew Python (at least somewhat decently), but I understand now there's a difference between using a language a few times, and actually knowing the language in and out.

My answer was... &quot;crap.&quot; I did not know what to do really, and it cost me the interview. I was ashamed, and now that I try it, I should've known it. 

The question was (I think): 


&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='console'&gt;&lt;span class='go'&gt;Remove the first letter from each word in the string: &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='gp'&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='s2'&gt;&amp;quot;asdf das f po&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

 
EDIT(2012-07-16): This was my March attempt.


&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='python'&gt;&lt;span class='c'&gt;# removes spaces from string&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='n'&gt;line&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;original&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='n'&gt;newline&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='s'&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='k'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;i&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ow'&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;line&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class='k'&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='nb'&gt;ord&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;!=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='p'&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nb'&gt;ord&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;&amp;#39; &amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;)):&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;span class='n'&gt;newline&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;+=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class='k'&gt;else&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;span class='k'&gt;pass&lt;/span&gt;
		
&lt;span class='k'&gt;print&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;newline&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='c'&gt;# removes first letter of each word from string &amp;amp; fix spacing&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='n'&gt;line&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;original&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='n'&gt;newword&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='s'&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='n'&gt;first&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='mi'&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='n'&gt;newline&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='p'&gt;[]&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='k'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;word&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ow'&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;line&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;split&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;():&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class='k'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;letter&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ow'&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;word&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;span class='k'&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;first&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;!=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='mi'&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
			&lt;span class='n'&gt;newword&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;+=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;letter&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;span class='k'&gt;else&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
			&lt;span class='n'&gt;first&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='mi'&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
			
	&lt;span class='n'&gt;first&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='mi'&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class='n'&gt;newline&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;append&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;newword&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class='n'&gt;newword&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='s'&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='n'&gt;output&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='p'&gt;[]&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='k'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;word&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ow'&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;newline&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class='k'&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;word&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='s'&gt;&amp;#39;&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ow'&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;word&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='s'&gt;&amp;#39; &amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;span class='k'&gt;pass&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class='k'&gt;else&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;span class='n'&gt;output&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;append&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;word&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='n'&gt;newline&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='s'&gt;&amp;quot; &amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;join&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;output&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='k'&gt;print&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;newline&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



EDIT(2012-07-16): How did I not realize how bad this was back when I wrote it? 
Wow. Just wow. I don't know how I made it this far programming if that was the best I could 
come up with. Honest.


&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='python'&gt;&lt;span class='k'&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='nf'&gt;removefirstletter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;sentence&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='p'&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class='n'&gt;tokens&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;sentence&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;split&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class='k'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;word&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='ow'&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='nb'&gt;range&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nb'&gt;len&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;tokens&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;)):&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;span class='n'&gt;tokens&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;word&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='s'&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;join&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nb'&gt;list&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;tokens&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;word&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;])[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='mi'&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;:])&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class='k'&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='s'&gt;&amp;quot; &amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;join&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;tokens&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


Easily handles any issue with spacing when you remove the word with one letter.

The output should be 


&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='console'&gt;&lt;span class='gp'&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='s2'&gt;&amp;quot;df as o&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


I'd like to think I made progress, but this could be done a lot better still. 
But if I got this far in 3 months, I'm can't think of the possibilities in a couple years!
&lt;/p&gt;</content>
   
   <category term="fail"/>
   
   <category term="interview"/>
   
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title type="html">hello world!</title>
   <link href="http://www.laivictor.com/archive/2012/02/25/helloworld"/>
   <updated>2012-02-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.laivictor.com/archive/2012/02/25/helloworld</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
This is my first post. So, an obligatory


&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='python'&gt;&lt;span class='k'&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='nf'&gt;main&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;():&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class='k'&gt;print&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='s'&gt;&amp;quot;Hello world!&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='k'&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;__name__&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='s'&gt;&amp;quot;__main__&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class='n'&gt;main&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


Thanks for visiting~
&lt;/p&gt;</content>
   
   <category term="misc"/>
   
 </entry>
 

</feed>
